xemarkets.com 2013-10-30

# Privacy Policy

We are committed to preserving the privacy of all visitors and users of this website. Please read the following privacy policy to understand how we use and protect the information that you provide to us. We will only use your personal information in accordance with the present Privacy Policy.

Our Privacy Policy Statement will be reviewed from time to time to take into account new laws and technology, changes to our operations and practices, and to ensure it remains appropriate to the changing environment. By using this website, you consent to us using your personal information as set out below.

## What personal information do we collect?

If you decide to apply to open an account with us, there is certain information that we will require from you in order to do so. This information includes but is not limited to personal details such as name, address, date of birth, contact details, employment details, assets and liabilities and other necessary financial information. From time to time we may also request further information to help us improve our services to you.

We obtain most of the information directly from our customers through application or other forms, and from maintaining records of information provided in the course of ongoing customer service. We may also collect information about your use of the website, such as pages visited, frequency and duration of visits and trading activities.

## How do we use this information?

We will use information collected from you to provide the information and services requested by you and to improve the quality of our services. Unless you are informed otherwise, the personal information we hold is used for:

  * Establishing and managing your account;
  * Reviewing your ongoing needs;
  * Enhancing customer service and products;
  * Giving you ongoing information or opportunities that we believe may be relevant to you.

## Disclosure of Information

Depending on the product or service concerned and particular restrictions on sensitive information, this means that personal information may be disclosed to our service providers and specialist advisers who have been contracted to provide us with administrative, financial, insurance, research or other services; introducing brokers with whom we have a mutual relationship (any of whom may be within or outside the European Economic Area), credit providers, courts, tribunals and regulatory authorities as agreed or authorized by law.

## Credit reporting or reference agencies

Personal information may also be disclosed to credit reporting or reference agencies, or to anyone authorized by an individual, as specified by that individual or the contract. In the case that you do not want us to use your personal information, please let us know in writing. If you decide to do so, we may not be able to continue to provide information, services and/or products requested by you and we will have no liability to you in respect of the same.

## Updating your information

You may inform **XM** at any time that your personal details have changed or that you wish **XM** to delete personal information we hold about you by e-mailing us to info@xm.com.

**XM** will change or delete your personal information in accordance with your instructions, except when we are required to hold your personal information for regulatory or legal purposes, or to provide you with the services you have requested, or to maintain adequate business records.

## Use of Cookies

If you open an account with us, you will need to use our trading software, which enables us to use cookies when you access our website. Cookies are small files of information, which often include a unique identification number or value, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive as a result of you using this trading software and accessing this website. The purpose of this information is to provide you with a more relevant and effective experience of our website, including the presentation of our web pages according to your needs or preferences. 

Cookies are frequently used on many websites on the Internet and you can choose if and how a cookie will be accepted by changing your preferences and options in your browser. You may not be able to access some parts of our website if you choose to disable the cookie acceptance in your browser, particularly the secure parts of the website. We therefore recommend you to enable cookie acceptance in order to benefit from all the services on our website.

Furthermore, we use cookies for remarketing features in order to allow us to reach out to users who have previously visited our website and have shown an interest in our products and services. From time to time, we may use third party vendors, such as Google and DoubleClick, to display our ads over the internet to you, based on your previous use of our website. You can opt out of this particular use of cookies at any time by visiting [Google’s Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) and the [ DoubleClick opt-out page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb#display_optout).

## What are your rights?

You have (subject to certain exceptions) the right to obtain any personal information which **XM** holds about you and inform **XM** of any perceived inaccuracy. To make a request, please write to us, verifying your identity and specifying what information you require. We may charge a fee to cover the cost of verifying the application and locating, retrieving, reviewing and copying any material requested. We will acknowledge your request and respond to it within 40 days of receipt of your application and any applicable fee.

## Amendments to policy

We reserve the right to change this policy at any time. If any changes are made, an updated version will be posted on this page.

**Risk Warning:** Forex, Commodities, Options and CFDs (OTC Trading) are leveraged products that carry a substantial risk of loss up to your invested capital and may not be suitable for everyone. Please ensure that you fully understand the risks involved and do not invest money you cannot afford to lose. Please refer to our full Risk Disclosure.
